<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#" xmlns:la="https://linked.art/ns/" xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cidoc-crm.org/cidoc-crm/">

<rdfs:Class rdf:about="E11_Modification">
	<rdfs:label xml:lang="ru">&#1057;&#1086;&#1073;&#1099;&#1090;&#1080;&#1077; &#1048;&#1079;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103;</rdfs:label>
	<rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Modification</rdfs:label>
	<rdfs:label xml:lang="el">&#932;&#961;&#959;&#960;&#959;&#960;&#959;&#943;&#951;&#963;&#951;</rdfs:label>
	<rdfs:label xml:lang="fr">Modification</rdfs:label>
	<rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Bearbeitung</rdfs:label>
	<rdfs:label xml:lang="pt">Modifica&#231;&#227;o</rdfs:label>
	<rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">&#20462;&#25913;</rdfs:label>
	<rdfs:comment>This class comprises all instances of E7 Activity that create, alter or change E24 Physical Human-Made Thing. 
This class includes the production of an item from raw materials, and other so far undocumented objects, and the preventive treatment or restoration of an object for conservation. 
Since the distinction between modification and production is not always clear, modification is regarded as the more generally applicable concept. This implies that some items may be consumed or destroyed in a Modification, and that others may be produced as a result of it. An event should also be documented using E81 Transformation if it results in the destruction of one or more objects and the simultaneous production of others using parts or material from the originals. In this case, the new items have separate identities. 
If the instance of the E29 Design or Procedure utilized for the modification prescribes the use of specific materials, they should be documented using property P68 foresees use of (use foreseen by): E57 Material of E29 Design or Procedure, rather than via P126 employed (was employed in): E57 Material.
</rdfs:comment>
	<rdfs:subClassOf rdf:resource="E7_Activity"/>
</rdfs:Class>

</rdf:RDF>
