<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#" xmlns:la="https://linked.art/ns/" xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cidoc-crm.org/cidoc-crm/">

<rdf:Property rdf:about="P65_shows_visual_item">
	<rdfs:label xml:lang="fr">pr&#233;sente l'item visuel</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">shows visual item</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">zeigt Bildliches</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ru">&#1087;&#1086;&#1082;&#1072;&#1079;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072;&#1077;&#1090; &#1074;&#1080;&#1079;&#1091;&#1072;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1099;&#1081; &#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1084;&#1077;&#1090;</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="el">&#949;&#956;&#966;&#945;&#957;&#943;&#950;&#949;&#953; &#959;&#960;&#964;&#953;&#954;&#972; &#963;&#964;&#959;&#953;&#967;&#949;&#943;&#959;</rdfs:label>
	<rdfs:label xml:lang="pt">apresenta item visual</rdfs:label>
	<rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">&#26174;&#31034;&#35270;&#35273;&#39033;&#30446;</rdfs:label>

	<rdfs:comment>This property documents an E36 Visual Item shown by an instance of E24 Physical Human-Made Thing.
This property is similar to P62 depicts (is depicted by) in that it associates an item of E24 Physical Human-Made Thing with a visual representation. However, P65 shows visual item (is shown by) differs from the P62 depicts (is depicted by) property in that it makes no claims about what the E36 Visual Item is deemed to represent. E36 Visual Item identifies a recognisable image or visual symbol, regardless of what this image may or may not represent.
For example, all recent British coins bear a portrait of Queen Elizabeth II, a fact that is correctly documented using P62 depicts (is depicted by). Different portraits have been used at different periods, however. P65 shows visual item (is shown by) can be used to refer to a particular portrait.
P65 shows visual item (is shown by) may also be used for Visual Items such as signs, marks and symbols, for example the 'Maltese Cross' or the 'copyright symbol&#8217; that have no particular representational content. 
This property is part of the fully developed path from E24 Physical Human-Made Thing through P65 shows visual item (is shown by), E36 Visual Item, P138 represents (has representation) to E1 CRM Entity which is shortcut by, P62 depicts (is depicted by).
</rdfs:comment>
	<rdfs:domain rdf:resource="E24_Physical_Human-Made_Thing"/>
	<rdfs:range rdf:resource="E36_Visual_Item"/>
	<rdfs:subPropertyOf rdf:resource="P128_carries"/>
<owl:inverseOf rdf:resource="P65i_is_shown_by"/>
</rdf:Property>

</rdf:RDF>
